Welcome back.
잘 돌아왔어요
You may, like me, have just gone off and got a coffee while things loaded back up again.
여러분도 저처럼 커피를 마시러 갔을지도 모릅니다 다시 짐을 싣는 동안에요
And back here.
여기도요
Uh, after the restart your session box, you needed to have come back and rerun the.
세션 박스를 재시작한 후 다시 돌아와서 재시작해야 했죠
You don't need to rerun the installs, but you need to rerun the imports.
설치한 건 재실행할 필요 없고 수입한 건 재실행해야 해요
The constants log in to hugging face again.
상수는 얼굴을 다시 안는 데 로그인하죠
Do not run this.
실행하지 마세요
Otherwise we'll be back where we were with a big model in memory.
안 그러면 메모리 모델로 되돌아가는 거예요
Uh, skip back to restart your session.
다시 세션을 시작하도록 하죠
And here we are loading the base model using eight bit.
8 비트를 이용해 기본 모델을 로딩하고 있어요
So again, you've seen this before.
전에도 보신 적 있죠
We did briefly.
잠깐요
Uh, at least have this in the code if I didn't mention much about it.
제가 말 안 했으면 코드에 적어뒀을 텐데요
Um, and it uses this wonderfully named there's a package called Bits and Bytes, uh, which is a great
이름도 참 잘 지었어요 비트 앤 바이트라는 패키지인데 패키지 이름으로
name for a package.
딱이죠
Uh, and you create a class called Bits and Bytes config, which is where you specify, uh, what kind
Bits&amp;Bite config라는 클래스를 생성하는데 여기서 명시하는 거죠
of quantization config you want, how, how much you want to reduce the precision of your model.
어떤 종류의 수량화 구성을 원하는지 모델의 정밀도를 얼마나 줄이고 싶은지를요
And we are saying load in eight bit is true.
8비트로 로드하는 게 참이죠
Uh, and then you when you load the base model, you pass that in as a parameter.
그리고 베이스 모델을 로드할 때 그걸 매개 변수로 넘겨요
As I said, we did do this in the past, I think, but we didn't talk much about it.
전에도 이런 적이 있지만 얘기를 많이 하진 않았어요
Um, so this is how we load in the llama 3.1 base model, with the precision reduced from 32 bits down
라마 3을 이렇게 싣는 거예요 기본 모델 1개를 32개에서 8개로 정밀하게
to eight bits.
줄였어요
Um, so I've run that because it takes a couple of minutes.
몇 분 정도 걸리니까 그렇게 했어요
And now let's look at the memory footprint that that's using up.
이제 메모리 발자국을 보죠
It's using up nine gigabytes just over nine gigs.
9기가바이트를 사용하고 있어요. 9기가를 조금 넘어요.
Uh, as you can see, if you look over here at the resources that we're using up nine gigs and we're
보다시피 여기 리소스를 보시면 9기가를 사용하고 있고 시스템
no longer having to spill into system memory.
메모리로 쏟아질 필요가 없어요
Uh, and let's have a look at that base model's architecture.
기본 모델의 아키텍처를 살펴보죠
So here then, is the model architecture after quantization.
여기 퀀타이즈 후의 모델 아키텍처가 있네요
Um, and now let me pause for a bit while, uh, to, for you to spot the difference.
차이점을 파악할 수 있게 잠시 비트를 멈출게요
Let's see what's changed in the architecture.
아키텍처에서 무엇이 바뀌었는지 보죠
Uh, now that we've quantized, I'll give you just a second to identify that challenge for you.
이제 퀀타이즈가 됐으니 도전 과제를 확인할 시간을 1초 드릴게요
And your time is up.
시간 다 됐어요
And, of course, you know that there's no difference in architecture.
물론 건축은 차이가 없어요
Trick question.
함정 질문이에요
Oh, don't hate me.
미워하지 마세요
Uh, so, yeah, there's no difference in architecture.
네, 건축학적으로 다른 점은 없어요
This is identical because the whole idea of quantization is that whilst we've reduced the precision
동일합니다 퀀타이즈의 전체적인 원리는 모델에서 각 숫자와
of each of the numbers, each of the weights in the model, we haven't actually changed the architecture
무게의 정밀도를 낮췄을 뿐 모델의 구조를 바꾸진 않았으니까요
And somewhat surprisingly, it's not going to have a massive effect on the performance of the model.
그리고 좀 놀랍게도 모델의 성능에 큰 영향을 주진 않아요
So hopefully unless I've made some horrible gaffe, this architecture is identical to the one above.
제가 실수를 한 게 아니라면 이 구조는 위층과 똑같을 거예요
You can just confirm and double check.
확인하고 다시 확인하세요
I haven't made any terrible mistake, but that's that is the whole idea of quantization.
큰 실수는 안 했지만 그게 퀀타이즈의 핵심이에요
We've got from 32GB down to nine gigabytes without, it seems, any, um, uh, well, we haven't yet
32GB에서 9기가바이트로 내려갔는데, 이건 마치 아직 본 적이 없지만, 중요한
seen, but without without without significant consequences.
결과가 없는 것 같아요.
There will be some consequences.
대가가 따를 거예요
Just not as big as you might expect.
생각만큼 크진 않지만요
Uh, so we will have to restart our sessions once more.
그래서 세션을 다시 시작해야 할 것 같아요
Uh, so for the final time, if I could ask you to restart your session as before, uh, runtime restart
마지막으로 세션을 다시 시작하도록 요청할게요 런타임 세션 다시 시작이요
session and then meet me back here again.
그리고 여기서 다시 만나요
Uh, after this point, once you've run the imports, the constants, uh, and logged into huggingface
이 시점 이후 수입, 상수를 실행하고 포옹페이스에 다시 로그인하면
again, I will see you in one second.
1초 후에 만나요